Historical Audiovisual Collection, 1912-2012 (bulk 1945-1996 ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 2: Alumni, 1916-2010; 234 items
  - Reunions, 1916-2010; 190 items
    - Class of 1888's 40th Reunion, 2009; 853; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      Annotated silent movie of the Class of 1888's 40th's reunion. Scenes include P-rade and sunday afternoon gathering at the residence of Prof. F. McClure '88. Transfer from 16mm. #1948, 187, 853 all on same tape. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam.
    - Bicentennial Celebration (Class of 1929), 2009; 913; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Scenes from the celebration of Princeton's 200th anniversary, focusing on the Class of 1929. Scenes include P-rade, baseball match (with Present Harold Dodds and his wife), and outdoor dining.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 6:55.
    - Bicentennial Celebration (Class of 1929), 2009; 913; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Scenes from the celebration of Princeton's 200th anniversary, focusing on the Class of 1929. Scenes include P-rade, baseball match (with Present Harold Dodds and his wife), and outdoor dining.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 6:55.
    - Bicentennial Celebration (Class of 1929), 2009; 913; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      Scenes from the celebration of Princeton's 200th anniversary, focusing on the Class of 1929. Scenes include P-rade, baseball match (with Present Harold Dodds and his wife), and outdoor dining. Transfer from 16mm. #47, 57, 66, 79, 89, 92, 106, 913 all on same tape. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam; Duration: 6:55.
    - Celebration of Coeducation at the Graduate School, 2009; 1306; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Panelists describe their experiences as women at the Graduate School, during a celebration of the introduction of coeducation for graduates in 1961. Speakers include Sabra Follett Meservey, the first woman to be enrolled as a full-time degree candidate at the Graduate School. Coeducation for undergraduates was introduced in 1969.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 1:32:27.
    - Celebration of Coeducation at the Graduate School, 2009; 1306; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Panelists describe their experiences as women at the Graduate School, during a celebration of the introduction of coeducation for graduates in 1961. Speakers include Sabra Follett Meservey, the first woman to be enrolled as a full-time degree candidate at the Graduate School. Coeducation for undergraduates was introduced in 1969.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 1:32:27.
    - Celebration of Coeducation at the Graduate School, 2009; Digital Files: 1
      Item number: 1306. Panelists describe their experiences as women at the Graduate School, during a celebration of the introduction of coeducation for graduates in 1961. Speakers include Sabra Follett Meservey, the first woman to be enrolled as a full-time degree candidate at the Graduate School. Coeducation for undergraduates was introduced in 1969. Duration: 1:32:27.
    - Class of 1921 - Graduation, 1923 and 1926 reunions, 2009; 1948; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      Item Annotated silent movie of the class of 1921's graduation (part I) and its 2nd and 5th reunion in 1923 and 1926 (part 2). Part 1 includes scenes of the P-rade and Princeton-Yale baseball match, named professors, trustees, and class members, including President Hibben and Colonel Libbey, followed by exercises with pipe smashing on Cannon Green. Part 2 includes varsity rowing against Cornell and Yale on Carnegie Lake, and reunion scenes for 1923 and 1926.. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam; Duration: 39:45.
    - Class of 1921 - Graduation, 1923 and 1926 reunions, 2009; 1948; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
      Annotated silent movie of the class of 1921's graduation (part I) and its 2nd and 5th reunion in 1923 and 1926 (part 2). Part 1 includes scenes of the P-rade and Princeton-Yale baseball match, named professors, trustees, and class members, including President Hibben and Colonel Libbey, followed by exercises with pipe smashing on Cannon Green. Part 2 includes varsity rowing against Cornell and Yale on Carnegie Lake, and reunion scenes for 1923 and 1926.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 39:45.
    - Class of 1921 - Graduation, 1923 and 1926 reunions, 2009; 1948; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
      Annotated silent movie of the class of 1921's graduation (part I) and its 2nd and 5th reunion in 1923 and 1926 (part 2). Part 1 includes scenes of the P-rade and Princeton-Yale baseball match, named professors, trustees, and class members, including President Hibben and Colonel Libbey, followed by exercises with pipe smashing on Cannon Green. Part 2 includes varsity rowing against Cornell and Yale on Carnegie Lake, and reunion scenes for 1923 and 1926.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 39:45.
    - Class day and commencement, circa 2009; 61; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
      Silent. Class of 1937. 16 mm; Duration: 4:09.
    - Class day and commencement, circa 2009; 61; 1 Disc(s) (Box 226)
      Silent. Class of 1937. Created by Princeton Media Services. DVD; Duration: 4:09.
    - Class Film of the Class of 1939, circa 2009; 199; 1 Disc(s) (Box 226)
      Class film of the class of 1939's undergraduate years, featuring freshmen football practice, the "Veterans of Future War," athletics, the Yale-Princeton game, Triangle (with Freddie Fox), ROTC training camp, House parties and Commencement.. Created by Princeton Media Services. DVD.
    - Princeton Reunions 2010 P-rade, AR.2015.003; 2384; 1 Disc(s) (Box 224)
      The Princeton Reunions DVD contains the following: 17 videos from 2010 Reunions (created by Dr. Kramer), 2 digitized videos from AC047 (outside of scope), 4 Office of Communication videos (outside of scope), and 1 Triangle club promo ad (scope).. Created by Kramer '67, Dr. Sandy. DVD.
    - Class of 1926, undated; 31; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 54)
    - Class of 1927, undated; 60; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
    - ROTC Horse-drawn Artillery Armistice Parade, undated; 136; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 134)
      Created by Grad. Council. 16 mm.
    - Class of 1933 Record Film and 1933 Reunion Film, undated; AR.1990.049; 842; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 180)
      Created by Undergraduate Motion Picture Company. 16 mm.
    - Class of 1923 Reunion, undated; 850; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 182)
    - Class of 1917, undated; 888; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 83)
    - Class of 1910 - Paul Cadwell, undated; 905; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 84)
    - Class of 1943, undated; AR.2001.063; 1304; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 25)
    - Class of 1973 - First Co-Educational Class, undated; AR.2001.063; 1328; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 26)
      VHS; Duration: 35 min 58 sec.
    - Class of 1921 - Graduation, 1931, 1932, 1933 and 1941 reunions, undated; 1949; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 189)
      16 mm; Duration: 25 min.
    - Class of 1921 - Graduation, 1931, 1938, 1940 and 1941 reunions, undated; 1950; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 189)
    - Going Back: Fifty-Two Members of the Class of 1952 Revisit Their Undergraduate Days, undated; AR.2008.089; 2017; 2 Disc(s) (Box 194)
      2 copies. Compact disc.
- Series 3: Campus Life, 1945-2009; 276 items
  The Campus Life series contains audiovisual materials pertaining to student life on campus. The series is arranged into three subseries: Social Life, Athletics, and War/Military.
  - Social life, 1945-2009; 64 items
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; AR.2008.013; 1980; 2 Film Reel(s) (Box 192)
      8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. "Job #6010 Reel #002" and "Job #6010 Reel #003". 8 mm; Duration: 10:10.
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; AR.2008.013; 1980; 2 Disc(s) (Box 192)
      8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. Copies of reels #002 and #003. DVD; Duration: 10:10.
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; 1980; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 192)
      8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. Job #6010 Reel #003. Created by Vidipax. Windows Media Audio/Video file; Duration: 10:10.
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; 1980; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 192)
      8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. Job #6010 Reel #002. Created by Vidipax. Windows Media Audio/Video file; Duration: 10:10.
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; Digital Files: 1
      Item number:1980. Part 1: Princeton scenes portion only. 8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. Duration: 10:10.
    - Lawrence Rauch - Princeton Scenes; Move of Corwin Hall to accommodate construction of Robertson Hall, 1945-1963; Digital Files: 1
      Intem number: 1980. Part 2: Corwin portion only. 8mm film, shot by Lawrence L. Rauch *49 presumably during his years as a graduate student at the Department of Mathematics, with miscellaneous Princeton scenes, including personal scenes with his wife, various buildings on campus, aerial shots of New York and Princeton, and football scenes.\n\n\n\n8mm film recording of the move of Corwin Hall from its site at Washington Road to its present site 100 ft further to accommodate the building of the Robertson Hall, the new building of the Woodrow Wilson School. The move of Corwin Hall, which housed the Woodrow Wilson School 1951-1965, took place on May 20, 1963. Duration: 10:10.
    - Scenes of Princeton, 1949-1951; AR.2000.071; 55; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 133)
      Created by William I. Homer. 16 mm.
    - Orange Key Master Film -- "An undergraduate view of Princeton University", 1962; 91; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 142)
      Staged instruction film for students participating in the Orange Key Guide Service, in which Charles W. Greenleaf '63, vice-president of the Keycept Program, discusses what distinguishes Princeton from other universities. \n\nThe film includes extensive footage of faculty and campus. Subjects discussed are: Faculty and the preceptorial system, with professors John Turkevich, chemistry, and Eric Goldman, history (3:30); independent research projects, with professor D.C. Hazen, aeronautical enginee; research at Firestone Library; freshman advisers; the honor system; financial aid; dormitories; extracurricular activities and sports. 16 mm; Duration: 25:27.
    - Committee on Governance --Woodrow Wilson, 1970; 613; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 80)
    - Committee on Governance --Woodrow Wilson, 1970; 614; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 80)
    - Occupation of Woodrow Wilson School, Anti ROTC Demonstration, circa 1971-1972; 1832; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 111)
    - WPRB - Provost Bowen with students during IDA sit-in in Nassau Hall, 1972 May 9; 2330; 1 Audio Reel(s) (Box 228)
      From AC195 (Office of the Provost Records) Series 1E, Box 22, Folder 4. 1/4 inch magnetic tape, 5-inch reel.
    - Residential Colleges and Wu Hall, 1982; AR.2001.063; 1327; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 26)
      Promotional film about the residential colleges, presented by President William Bowen, with particular emphasis on the newly completed Gordon Wu Hall. VHS; Duration: 1:30.
    - Residential Colleges and Wu Hall, 1982; 1327; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Promotional film about the residential colleges, presented by President William Bowen, with particular emphasis on the newly completed Gordon Wu Hall.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 1:30.
    - Residential Colleges and Wu Hall, 1982; 1327; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Promotional film about the residential colleges, presented by President William Bowen, with particular emphasis on the newly completed Gordon Wu Hall.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 1:30.
    - Residential Colleges and Wu Hall, 1982; Digital Files: 1
      Item number: 1327. Promotional film about the residential colleges, presented by President William Bowen, with particular emphasis on the newly completed Gordon Wu Hall. Duration: 1:30.
    - PUWO c/o Princeton Weekly Bulletin, J. Savani, 1986; 1876; 1 Audiocassette(s) (Box 112)
    - student protests - negotiations between students/adminstrators over occupation of President Shapiro's office to increase SHARE funding and staff, 1990; 1557; 2 Disc(s) (Box 212)
      day 1, Doris Lessing interview, day 2. Created by Princeton Media Services. Compact disc.
    - student protests - negotiations between students/adminstrators over occupation of President Shapiro's office to increase SHARE funding and staff, 1990; AR.2001.067; 1557; 2 Audiocassette(s) (Box 104)
      day 1, Doris Lessing interview, day 2. Compact cassette.
    - Princeton Quadrangle Club, 1994; AR.1994.026; 578; 3 Videocassette(s) (Box 44)
    - Princeton's 250th Anniversary - "Defining Moments: Princeton at 250" short version, 1995; 1369; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 8)
    - Princeton's 250th Anniversary - "Defining Moments: Princeton at 250" long version, 1995; AR.1996.006; 1579; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 7)
      Created by Greenspan/Allen. Betacam SP; Duration: 31 min 20 sec.
    - Princeton Fall '95 - in church, 1995 September 26; AR.2007.034; 2323; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 208)
      Used by Robert Allen and Greenspan to make the Goheen video (item #2025). Tape #7. Created by A. Greenspan and Assoc./Rob Rainey Video, Inc. Betacam SP.
    - Princeton's 250th Anniversary - Princeton: Images of a University, 1996; 1362; 2 Videocassette(s) (Box 200)
      2 copies. Created by Trustees of Princeton University. VHS.
    - Princeton's 250th Anniversary - Princeton: Images of a University, 1996; AR.2011.101; 1362; 1 Disc(s) (Box 200)
      Created by Trustees of Princeton University. DVD.
    - "How to build the Friend Center in four mintues", 2001 September 29; AR.2017.125; 2393; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 234)
      Created by The Friend Center. Betacam SP.
    - "How to build the Friend Center in four mintues", 2001 September 29; AR.2017.125; 2394; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 234)
      Created by The Friend Center. VHS.
    - "How to build the Friend Center in four mintues", 2001 September 29; AR.2017.125; 2395; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 234)
      This is a SVHS tape. Created by The Friend Center. VHS.
    - Princeton Stills, 2006 August 23; AR.2007.034; 2316; 5 Videocassette(s) (Box 210)
      Used by Robert Allen and Greenspan to make the Goheen video (item #2025). Betacam SP.
    - Orange Key Master Film -- "An undergraduate view of Princeton University", 2009; 91; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      Staged instruction film for students participating in the Orange Key Guide Service, in which Charles W. Greenleaf '63, vice-president of the Keycept Program, discusses what distinguishes Princeton from other universities. \n\nThe film includes extensive footage of faculty and campus. Subjects discussed are: Faculty and the preceptorial system, with professors John Turkevich, chemistry, and Eric Goldman, history (3:30); independent research projects, with professor D.C. Hazen, aeronautical enginee; research at Firestone Library; freshman advisers; the honor system; financial aid; dormitories; extracurricular activities and sports. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam; Duration: 25:27.
    - Orange Key Master Film -- "An undergraduate view of Princeton University", 2009; 91; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
      Staged instruction film for students participating in the Orange Key Guide Service, in which Charles W. Greenleaf '63, vice-president of the Keycept Program, discusses what distinguishes Princeton from other universities. \n\nThe film includes extensive footage of faculty and campus. Subjects discussed are: Faculty and the preceptorial system, with professors John Turkevich, chemistry, and Eric Goldman, history (3:30); independent research projects, with professor D.C. Hazen, aeronautical enginee; research at Firestone Library; freshman advisers; the honor system; financial aid; dormitories; extracurricular activities and sports. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 25:27.
    - Orange Key Master Film -- "An undergraduate view of Princeton University", 2009; 91; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 223)
      Staged instruction film for students participating in the Orange Key Guide Service, in which Charles W. Greenleaf '63, vice-president of the Keycept Program, discusses what distinguishes Princeton from other universities. \n\nThe film includes extensive footage of faculty and campus. Subjects discussed are: Faculty and the preceptorial system, with professors John Turkevich, chemistry, and Eric Goldman, history (3:30); independent research projects, with professor D.C. Hazen, aeronautical enginee; research at Firestone Library; freshman advisers; the honor system; financial aid; dormitories; extracurricular activities and sports. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 25:27.
    - Polo, Eating Clubs and ROTC, 2009; 132; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 134)
      This silent movie, possibly shot by an alumnus visiting with his wife and son, includes a polo match, shots of Nassau Street and the eating clubs, and an inspection of Princeton's ROTC Field Artillery Unit by Major General Hanson E. Ely on May 9, 1928. 16 mm; Duration: 15:40.
    - Polo, Eating Clubs and ROTC, 2009; 132; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      This silent movie, possibly shot by an alumnus visiting with his wife and son, includes a polo match, shots of Nassau Street and the eating clubs, and an inspection of Princeton's ROTC Field Artillery Unit by Major General Hanson E. Ely on May 9, 1928.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 15:40.
    - Polo, Eating Clubs and ROTC, 2009; 132; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      This silent movie, possibly shot by an alumnus visiting with his wife and son, includes a polo match, shots of Nassau Street and the eating clubs, and an inspection of Princeton's ROTC Field Artillery Unit by Major General Hanson E. Ely on May 9, 1928.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 15:40.
    - Polo, Eating Clubs and ROTC, 2009; 132; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      This silent movie, possibly shot by an alumnus visiting with his wife and son, includes a polo match, shots of Nassau Street and the eating clubs, and an inspection of Princeton's ROTC Field Artillery Unit by Major General Hanson E. Ely on May 9, 1928.. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam; Duration: 15:40.
    - The Building of Firestone, 2009; 187; 1 Film Reel(s) (Box 164)
      Scenes from the beginning of the construction of Firestone Library. 16 mm; Duration: 14:21.
    - The Building of Firestone, 2009; 187; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Scenes from the beginning of the construction of Firestone Library.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 14:21.
    - The Building of Firestone, 2009; 187; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Scenes from the beginning of the construction of Firestone Library.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 14:21.
    - The Building of Firestone, 2009; 187; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 196)
      Scenes from the beginning of the construction of Firestone Library.. Created by Colorlab. Digital Betacam; Duration: 14:21.
    - The Building of Firestone, 2009; 187; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 223)
      Scenes from the beginning of the construction of Firestone Library. U-matic; Duration: 14:21.
    - Center for Jewish Life Student Video, 2009; 569; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 43)
      Promotional video about being Jewish at Princeton University and the Center for Jewish Life.. Created by Ambassador Resources. VHS; Duration: 11:32.
    - Center for Jewish Life Student Video, 2009; 569; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Promotional video about being Jewish at Princeton University and the Center for Jewish Life.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 11:32.
    - Center for Jewish Life Student Video, 2009; 569; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Promotional video about being Jewish at Princeton University and the Center for Jewish Life.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 11:32.
    - Center for Jewish Life Student Video, 2009; Digital Files: 1
      Item number: 569. Promotional video about being Jewish at Princeton University and the Center for Jewish Life. Duration: 11:32.
    - Princeton University - Halftime Promotional Spot, 2009; AR.2001.063; 1325; 1 Videocassette(s) (Box 26)
      Halftime promotional spot about Princeton University, using stills only.. Created by Falcon Video Studios. VHS; Duration: 3:44.
    - Princeton University - Halftime Promotional Spot, 2009; 1325; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Halftime promotional spot about Princeton University, using stills only.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-2; Duration: 3:44.
    - Princeton University - Halftime Promotional Spot, 2009; 1325; 1 Digital File(s) (Box 222)
      Halftime promotional spot about Princeton University, using stills only.. Created by Colorlab. MPEG-4; Duration: 3:44.
    - Princeton University - Halftime Promotional Spot, 2009; Digital Files: 1